

PERSONAL

Name & Surname Aymelek YONAT

Current residence Debrecen (Hungary)

Phone number +905458959110

⊠ E-Mail melekyonat@gmail.com

📛 Date of birth 07/1992

Solution Country of birth **TURKEY**

☐ Driver's license B (Passenger car)

Aymelek YONAT

I am a biologist with 5 years of work experience in the Pharmaceutical Industry. During my work in microbiology laboratories, I have gained experience in the fields of Quality Control (QC) and Good Manufacture Practice (GMP) while also getting practice in a wide variety of processes, from gram staining tests to automated blood culture systems.

EDUCATION

04/09/2023 -

University of Debrecen, Debrecen (Hungary)

English Language Course

07/09/2011 – 31/08/2015 Eskişehir Osmangazi University, Eskişehir (Turkey)

4-year Bachelor Degree in Biology



WORK EXPERIENCE

16/09/2021 - 19/08/2022 Osel-Haver Pharmacy, Istanbul (Turkey)

Microbiology Specialist

As a microbiology specialist, I worked in the microbiology laboratory applying my knowledge about the various tests, operations and processes. I received training on devices such as fully automated blood culture systems (BD Bactec™), automated systems for the rapid identification of bacteria and antimicrobial susceptibility testing (BD) Phoenix[™]), sterility tests, endotoxin tests and carried out method validation studies.

03/02/2020 - 01/08/2021

Tüm Ekip Pharmacy, Istanbul (Turkey)

Microbiology Research Analyst

Applying the knowledge acquired in my previous workplaces, I contributed to the development and manufacture of antibiotics routinely used during the COVID-19 pandemic. Furthermore, my years of experience in microbiology laboratories has given me the ability to follow and pursue the improvement of Good Manufacture Practices.

13/11/2018 - 01/02/2020

Medicavet Pharmacy, Istanbul (Turkey)

Microbiology Research Analyst

I have done every analysis from the raw materials to the finished products in the microbiology laboratory of this veterinary medicine company. I performed cleaning validation, environmental controls, process and method validations, qualifications, water analysis, gel clot and endotoxin tests, disinfectant effectiveness tests, bioburden analysis, nitrogen air analysis, bacteria identification with API kits, gram staining tests and quantification analysis.

02/05/2016 - 13/07/2017

DİATEK, Istanbul (Turkey)

Biologist at Laboratory Production and Quality Control Department

I took an active part in the planning, making and quality control stages of the production of diagnostic equipment. I gained knowledge about making and using of various products used in the laboratory.

20/06/2013 - 15/08/2013

Geçit Kuşağı Agricultural Research Inst., Eskişehir (Turkey) Internship

Research and development were carried out in order to increase the productivity of agricultural products.

- Nitrogenous fertilizer agriculture

- Aspiration hybridization
- Plant sampling

VOLUNTEERING SCHOLARSHIPS

26/08/2022 – 10/04/2023 European Solidarity Corps, Oradea (Romania)

Global Volunteer

I worked as a volunteer in a project of European Solidarity Corps (program of European Union) in Oradea (Romania). We provided courses for children, youths and adults that included: acting, theatre classes, philosophy and art education, fashion design, ecological education, cinema. We also organized various events, conferences and festivals for locals.

01/04/2018 – 01/06/2018 Erasmus+, Vâlcea (Romania)

Global Volunteer

I joined a volunteer project in Romania for two months. It was focused around protecting nature. We have taught high school students the importance of protecting nature, and we designed various activities for them in this topic.

15/07/2017 - 05/09/2017 AIESEC Empower Women, Cairo (Egypt)

Global Volunteer

I took part in a volunteering project on the rights of Sudanese women who had to immigrate to Egypt after the war. The first aim of our project was to remind all refugee women that they have their own power and can change their world with this power. We tried to bring them back to life by organizing them English education, theatre, or various activities to put a smile on their faces. Secondly, we gave the Egyptian kids an alternative worldview to change their attitude and teach them to improve their perspectives. Thanks to this project, I have developed my ability to work in an international and multicultural team in order to achieve our goals together. With this project, I gained valuable experiences, especially in human relations.



LANGUAGES

Turkish (native) **English** Romanian





SKILLS

Microsoft Word, Microsoft Excel, QDMS Quality Management Solutions



HOBBIES

Camping & Trekking, Swimming, Dancing



REFERENCES

Osel-Haver Pharmacy - Microbiology Lab Manager Emel ÖZBAY - +905393550658

TÜM Ekip Pharmacy - Microbiology Lab Manager Talia ÖZTÜRK - +905373309885

Medicavet Pharmacy - Microbiology Lab Manager Pelin ANKAN - +905465783501